Laura Gwendolyn Burch

Seattle Washington

Phone: 682-365-9727 | Email: lauraburch.lb@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/laura-gwendolyn-burch/ GitHub: https://github.com/LauraGwendolynBurch

Portfolio: https://lauragwendolynburch.github.io/Portfolio 2.0/

SUMMARY

I am a Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Entertainment and teaching movement. My career has been built around working with people and building connections. Communication and project management are my biggest strengths. They are a passion I share with all projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML | CSS | JAVASCRIPT | NODE.JS | OOP

Applications: API calls

PROJECTS

Pub-Lish

https://github.com/LauraGwendolynBurch/Pub-Lish https://lauragwendolynburch.github.io/Pub-Lish/

- MVP of the first group project in Bootcamp | Helps users design their own pub crawl based on a US city search.
- Worked out local storage | Designed the layout | Wrote readMe
- HTML | CSS | Jquery | MapBox | API Calls

Quiz Your Code

https://github.com/LauraGwendolynBurch/Quiz_Your_Code https://lauragwendolynburch.github.io/Quiz_Your_Code/

- A javascript based code about circus trivia
- First use of local storage
- HTML | CSS | Vanilla JAVASCRIPT

Weather Watcher

https://github.com/LauraGwendolynBurch/Weather_Watcherhttps://lauragwendolynburch.github.io/Weather_Watcher/

- A city location based weather app
- Appends calles cities to a side list | Calls 5 day forecast | Recalls forecast if side list city is clicked again
- OpenWeather api keys | Moment.js | Bootstrap

Auto ReadME

https://github.com/LauraGwendolynBurch/Auto_ReadME https://lauragwendolynburch.github.io/Auto_ReadME/

- Automatically generate a readME file
- Use node.js and temperate literals to generate a quality readme file
- Node.js | Inquirer

EXPERIENCE

Aerialist | Designer | Manager | Creator Circus Kirkus

Jan-Mar 2020

Helped my Partner start a touring tent circus from the ground up | Consulted on logo design, promotional design, tent layout, and menu creation | Drove tent from city to city | Helped with tent build and break down | Worked the ticket booth | Managed front of house and cast schedule | Performed 2 unique aerial acts in each show along with group dance numbers | Musical and creative design of the show

 "Laura Gwendolyn Burch is one of the only aerialists in the world today creating her own material on silks that is thoughtful, intriguing, and innovative."
Julia Langenberg, Aerial Horizon San Antonio

Aerialist | Front of House Manager Venardos Circus

July 2018-Nov 2019

Three different contracts, spanning a year and half, touring coast to coast | Stilt Walking for Pre-Show and PR | Principle aeralist for all shows | Managed the ticket booth and all ticket sales | Build and breakdown of tent | Helped create guidelines for efficient workflow for ticketing and tent build

 Over the course of the tour created and performed 7 different aerial acts on 4 different apparatuses

Bartender 2016-2018 El Camino Seattle , WA

Main bartender/sometime server for high volume, trendy, Mexican restaurant | First female bartender in restaurants history | Keyholder | Developed craft cocktail menu | Built strong customer base | Multitasking in high stress environment

Yoga Teacher 2009-Current Bikram Yoga

Over 1000 hours of continuing education in kinesiology and anatomy | Cadaver labs | Group and private lessons | Workshops | Traveling Teacher

 "She is the Lady Gaga of Bikram instructors. If I had my own studio, I would hire her, get DNA samples from her skin, and clone another 10 Laura's to staff my fleet of teachers."
Former Student, Dallas, Texas

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Washington: March 2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on programming skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Degree or Certification:

Balanced Body Mat 1 Pilates: Certificate 2018

Northwest Academy for the Healing Arts: Certificate 2015

Bikram Yoga Teacher Training: Certificate 2009

Dallas College El Centro Campus: Associate Degree | Pattern Making and Apparel Design 2008

University of Texas at Arlington: General Studies 2001-2003